

Adel Ferdjoukh

Software Technical Leader



32 years



Toulouse, France



+33 695 55 89 13



ferdjoukh@gmail.com

About me ———

PhD. in software engineering. Worked in 4 universities (France & Austria). Currently Software Technical Leader at *Sopra Steria* in Toulouse. I conceive software for engineers using Java, Angular, Python, Agile and DevOps, participate in R&D projects, supervise developers and interns, answer RfQs and create software trainings.

Main Skills —

Java

Eclipse RCP, EMF

JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular

DevOps

Agile

Others:

Python, Bash, VersionOne, Maven, Artifactory, Kanban, Git, Jenkins, SonarQube, LDAP, Ontologies, Kubernetes, Docker

Languages —

French, English, German (beginner)

Experience

since 2022 Software Technical Leader Sopra Steria

Designing & developing software for Airbus flight test department using Java, Angular in agile and DevOps framework. Supervising the

work of other developers.

2019-2022 Software Technical Leader Capgemini Engineering

Developed and supervised developers for Airbus, Bosch. RFQ an-

swers. Gave Trainings on Software Methods.

2018 Researcher & Teacher Technische Universitat Wien

Conducting research on Model Driven Engineering and giving courses

on Graphical Modelling in English

2016-2018 Researcher & Teacher Universite de Nantes

Responsible of students groups for many computer science courses : programming, databases, web programming and I conducted re-

searches on Model Driven Engineering

2013-2016 Young Researcher Universite de Montpellier

Preparing a PhD in computer science at *Lirmm* research lab and teach-

ing computer science courses in the Faculty of Sciences

Education

2016 Ph.D. in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

A Declarative Approach for Model Generation

2013 Master in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

Specializing in Software Engineering

Notable Facts

Industrials 3 Airbus departments, Bosch Automotive, Dassault Systems

Teaching +850 hours teaching in 4 universities, +10 different topics and train-

ings for engineers.

Publications 10 papers in journal, international conferences or workshops

Best Paper ICSEA 2017, Athens, Greece

Talks Montpellier, Nantes, Lille, Angers, Paris, Bordeaux, Washington DC,

San Francisco, Oslo, Copenhagen, Athens & Vienna.

Certification Professional Scrum Master I

Current & Past Projects

Airbus fl. test Technical Leader & Developer

2022 →

Design the migration of a 10 years web application to Angular. Up to

4 people. JS/TS, Angular, LDAP, DevOps

Altran R&D Researcher & Project Leader 2022 →

Develop a cockpit simu. replay tool using: Java, DevOps(Jenkins,

Kubernetes, Docker, Arinc429)

Airbus DesignTechnical Leader & Developer 3.5 years

Workbenches for various aerodynamics studies, up to 5 people, using

: Eclipse RCP, Java, Git, DevOps and Python

Bosch Advanced Developer 1 year

A platform for car ECU parametrization, 30 developers. using: Java,

Eclipse RCP, Scrum and DevOps

Airbus DesignSoftware Architect & Developer 1 year

A tool for MDOptimization studies. Java, Python, Gemseo

Airbus Simu. Architect & Scrum Master 6 months

Design an application for enhancing legacy tool interoperability. Java,

DevOps, Model-Based